准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
深海餐车
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
蟹堡王到处都是客人还有客人的钱
Me restaurant is packed to the gills
with customers and their money
蟹老板  收银机又塞满了
Mr. Krabs, the register is full again
我来处理  章鱼哥先生
I got it, Mr. Squidward
你怎么没排队
Why aren't you in line?
不想吃蟹黄堡吗
Don't you want a Krabby Patty?
我确实想吃  可走过去太远了
I'd love one, but it's so far away
打包堡
口感没蟹黄堡好
Not quite as good as a Krabby Patty
不过我一英寸都用不着走
but I didn't have to move one inch
那餐车把我客人偷走了
That food truck stole me customer
要是客人不来蟹堡王
Well, if the customers won't come to the Krusty Krab
那我就把蟹堡王带给客人
I'll bring the Krusty Krab to them
蟹老板  我们到外面来干什么
Mr. Krabs, what are we doing out here?
你的大方老板有惊喜要给你
Your generous employer has a surprise for you
我好爱你的惊喜  蟹老板
I love your surprises, Mr. Krabs
我最爱的惊喜就是橡皮支票了
My favorite surprise was the rubber check
太好笑了
That was a good one
蟹堡王
看好了
Behold
我的全新  至少我这么觉得
Me brand new--to me--
餐车  蟹堡巡游舰
food truck, the Krusty Kruiser
好一堆垃圾
What a hunk of junk
好一辆大帅车才对
More like a big hunk of gorgeous
咱可不开那破车卖蟹黄堡
We won't sell any patties from that old jalopy
给我把蟹黄堡卖出去  否则不准回来
You better sell a patty or you better not come back
还有章鱼哥先生
And Mr. Squidward
你来开车
you're driving
我可以导航
I can navigate
好高兴
Joy
服务客人
Customers, ho
快点开
Get going
就只缺靠近饿肚子顾客的车位了
Now all we need is a parking spot
next to lots of hungry customers
那个位子不错  章鱼哥
That looks like a good spot, Squidward
隔油池
那可是我位子  讨厌鬼
That's my spot, you creep
停那边吧
Try over there
蝌蚪卷饼
我这边找到了空位
I found an empty spot in here
闭嘴
Shut it
建筑工人一下子就会饿着
Construction workers are always hungry
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties
来买热乎乎的蟹黄堡
Get your red-hot Krabby Patties
吊车煎饼
占我摊位的
You claim jumpers
这可是我地盘
This is my turf
用餐愉快
Bon appétit
这地方挺有格调
Now this place looks classy
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties
快来买美味平价蟹黄堡
Get your delicious, affordable Krabby Patties here
平价
Affordable?
平平无奇
How common
法式开胃小菜车
Canapé truck
上流法式开胃小菜
都走遍全裤头村了  啥都卖不出去
We tried all over Bikini Bottom and didn't sell a thing
回去跟蟹老板说我们失败了
Time to go back and tell Krabs we failed
咱还有一个地方没去试过
There's one place we still haven't tried
石头滩
Rock Bottom
快转  快转
Turn, turn
您正在驶出裤头村
石头滩
则所
这地方也太荒凉了
This place is deserted
没记错的话
If I recall correctly
唐果
公交站那边会有石头滩的好心居民
there are always
friendly Rock Bottomites at the bus stop
公较
你想得可真美啊  海绵宝宝
What a fabulous idea, SpongeBob
这里客人可真多啊
There are so many customers here
可能都在石头滩商场
Maybe the Rock Bottom mall?
商场
The mall
石头滩商场
人去哪了
Where is everybody?
去马戏团的应该比较多
The circus should be good for crowds
怕是都去跳蚤马戏团了
Maybe it's a flea circus?
还是温的
It's still warm
募地
墓地也没人
The cemetery is empty too
这地方连鬼城都算不上
This place isn't even a ghost town
行  咱尽力了
Well, we tried
回去吧
Let's go home
有客人
A customer
快来买好吃又稍微新鲜的
Step right up and get a delicious, half-fresh
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
他在那
There he is
凯皮吉
他去哪了
Where did he go?
在上面
Up there
这回一定要抓到他
I got him this time
跟丢他了
We lost him
他在那
There he is
能回去了吗
Can we go home now?
蟹老板说想要回来
Mr. Krabs said we can't go back
至少得卖出一个蟹黄堡
until we sell at least one Krabby Patty
好  那我就自己买蟹黄堡了
Fine, I'll just buy a stupid patty myself
什么
What?
我钱包忘在放家里的裤子里了
Forgot my wallet in my pants at home
海绵宝宝  你能不能
Oh, SpongeBob, could you please
借我一点钱买个蟹黄堡啊
lend me some money to buy a patty?
我只带了蟹堡币
I only carry Krusty Kash
在蟹堡王无效
"Not valid at the Krusty Krab"?
看来要想回去的话
I guess if I ever want to go home
就只能把蟹黄堡卖给神秘怪人了
we have to sell a patty to that mysterious weirdo
没问题
No problem
我来用我的捉水母技能追踪他
I'll track him down using my jellyfishing expertise
公较总占
逮到你了
Got ya
我的脑干
My brainstem
我看丛林鱼漫画学到的这招
I learned this trick reading Jungle Fish Comics
逮到那个小浑蛋了
Got the little barnacle
公较
既然都回不去了
Well, since I'm never going home
还是在这舒服一下好了
I may as well get comfortable
是你们这群怪人
You're those weirdos that have been
追着我到处跑
Chasing me around town
那你又干嘛朝我们招手
Why were you waving at us
然后又跑走
and then running away?
我听不懂你的口音
I can't understand your accent
我来处理  章鱼哥
I'll handle this, Squidward
我石头滩话说得可流利了
I speak fluid Rock Bottom-ish
为什么
Why
你要
Were you
朝我们招手
Waving at us?
我没
I wasn't
朝你们招手
Waving at you
是在
I was
扇干我胳肢窝
Drying out my armpits
我们只是想
We just wanted to
给你卖个热乎的
Sell you a hot
美味蟹黄堡
Delicious Krabby Patty
看起来还
It does look
挺好吃
Tasty
蟹黄堡要卖出去了
We're gonna sell a patty
伯特
Hey, Bert
真可惜你没办法
Too bad you couldn't
一起每年例行去一趟
Come with us on our yearly trip to the
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
不过蟹黄堡还是给你买了
But here's your Krabby Patties
谢谢  弗兰克
Thanks, Frank
不过要扇干胳肢窝真挺久的
But you know how long these pits take to dry
两位抱歉了
Sorry, fellas
虽然本来想向你们买蟹黄堡
I'd love to buy a patty from ya
不过我手上已经有一整袋了
but I already have a whole bag
石头滩居民好爱吃蟹黄堡
Those Rock Bottomers
really love their Krabby Patties
海绵宝宝  章鱼哥
SpongeBob, Squidward
你们回来了
you're back
卖了多少蟹黄堡
How many patties did you sell?
没
None
你们一整天都在搞什么名堂
What in the name of all that's greasy
have you been doing all day?
马上回去  卖不出蟹黄堡不准回来
You're going right back out there until you sell a patty
抱歉  小子
Sorry, boys
我有点饿
I'm a little hangry
我都已经忙得都没空吃东西了
I've been so busy, I haven't eaten anything meself
总共
That'll be
五块钱
Five bucks
好  行
All right, fine
反正这钱还会归我
Comes straight back to me pocket anyhow
耶
Yay
总算卖出一个蟹黄堡了
We finally sold a Krabby Patty
终于能回家了
I can finally go home
花了钱  味道就跟蜗牛砂一个样了
When I have to pay for it, it tastes like old snail litter
上流闺蜜
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜指导
统筹
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
快点
Let's go
赶紧的
Come on
这是在磨蹭什么
What's the hold up in there?
你表现得跟没做过蟹黄堡似的
You're acting like
you've never cooked a Krabby Patty before
是啊  老爸
Yeah, Dad
因为我本来就没做过蟹黄堡
that's because I never have
cooked a Krabby Patty before
你干嘛要我做这个
Why are you making me do this?
因为今天是带
Because today is bring--
我是说  让女儿上班日
I mean, put your daughter to work day
并且海绵宝宝还在忙着清理木桶椅呢
Besides, SpongeBob is busy
deep cleaning the barrel chairs
请问你介不介意
Do you mind?
完全不介意
Oh, no, not at all
你的餐到了
Here's your food or whatever
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
嗨  珍珍
Hi, Pearl
这是不是你最棒的工作啊
Isn't this just the best job ever?
你好啊  海绵宝宝
How do, SpongeBob
娜琳
Narlene
你弟弟诺比在哪
Where's your brother, Nobby?
女士好
Ma'am
我跟诺比要去大城市
Me and Nobby was just on our way to the big city
所以我们就想接受你的邀请
so we thought we'd take you up on your offer to
让你带我们观光
show us the sights
可以啊
I'd love to
裤头村
咱们能跟我最爱的消防栓打招呼
We can say hi to my favorite fire hydrant
还能看喂蛤蜊的老人家
and then we can see the old man that feeds the clams
还能
and then--
不行
no
我不能抛弃那些可可爱爱的人
I can't abandon these lovely people
要不就让我来带你们参观大城市吧
Then why don't I show you around the big city?
我才不稀罕别人
I don't care about these people
小珍珍要带我们去冒险吗
Little Pearly's gonna take us on an adventure?
太好了
Hot dippity
能让我离开这就行
Anything to get out of this place
鲸鱼愉快出游
It'll be a whale's day out
辛勤工作
Hard day's work
诺比说他要准备留下
Nobby says he's fixing to stay
帮海绵宝宝给饿肚子客人做蟹黄堡
and help SpongeBob with the hungry folk
珍珍  看来咱们赚大发了
So, Pearl, looks like we got ourselves a deal
好
Okay
一定会特别棒的
This'll be great
两位鲸鱼姐妹一起探索大城市
Two whale gals reconnoitering the big city together
要想一起去什么索大城市
If we want to do that "noitering" thing in the city
我得提前预支一下我零花钱
I'll need an advance on my allowance
老爸
Oh, Daddy
好  这就给你
All right, here you go
爸  拿木头会员卡才没法愉快出游
Dad, we can't have a whale's day out
with your balsa wood card
鲤事达
尤金蟹先生
我们要钻石不限量会员卡
We need the diamond unlimited
鲤事达
尤金蟹先生
我的钻石
My diamond
我以前从来没坐过潜水员
I never took a Scuber before
真的太方便了
but it sure is mighty convenient
感谢你载我一程
'Preciate the lift
好家伙
I'll be
大街上铺了口香糖
These city streets is paved with chewing candy
我要把你留着做纪念
I'm saving you as a souvenir
好吃
Tasty
大城市里还有不少不恶心的东西
The city also has a lot of things in it that aren't gross
真的吗
Really?
比如说这些奢华小屋吗
Like these fancy shacks here?
对  那是摩天大楼
Yeah, these are skyscrapers
那个呢
And that?
公交站
那是公交
That's public transportation
他在干什么
What's he doing?
道路施工
Street construction
感觉就好像在穿越一部电视节目一样
Why, it's like walking through a TV show
薯条
The fries
要是能够得到就好了
If only I could reach them
谢了  诺比
Thanks, Nobby
要是调料能再近点就好了
Now if only the condiments were closer
给你
Here you go
可惜面包架在厨房另一边
Too bad the bun rack is on the other side of the room
好耶
Oh, yeah
这样才叫快餐
This is what I call fast food
这里是我最爱的百货店
This is my favorite department store
上流百货
而且还是大城市的心脏
and, like, the heart of the big city
上流百货
Upturn's
这自动门太高档了
These here automatic doors sure is frilly
不过我们山民做事更礼貌
but we hill folk do things a little more polite-like
这边请  先生
Right this way, sir
不好意思
Excuse me
你这是在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
帮人扶门啊
Holding the door
来  你试试
Here, you try
娜琳  那是上流小姐
Narlene, that's Lady Upturn
对不起
I'm so sorry
她刚进城
She's new in town
我们会乖乖购物的
but we'll be good shoppers
我发誓
I swear
好
Yes
可以
All right
去买吧  我的消费主义者
carry on, my little consumerists
但在上流百货这里购物一定要严肃
But here at Upturn's, we take shopping seriously
好
Okay
上流香水
欢迎光临香水商店
Welcome to the perfume department
好像有什么东西死在里面了
I think something done died up in here
死完上天堂了
Died and went to heaven
好
Yeah
龙涎香
Ambergris
我
I--
你搞什么
Why, you
什么事
Yes?
你有什么毛病
What's your problem?
我得清理一下你这边的过道
I've got a cleanup on aisle you
要不然再帮你试喷一点香水好了
Perhaps another sample spritz?
抱歉  我对那种恶臭不是很讲究
Sorry, but I ain't too 'ticular about that stench
真的
Really
并且我还有自己特色的臭气
Besides, I carry my own signature stink
毒蘑菇味
Toadstool tang
我的鼻子
My nose
臭死了
The horrible stench
走了  赶快逃吧
Come on, we better cheese it
这件酷裙子好不好看
What do you think about this cool dress?
更衣室
不好说
I don't know
有点紧
It's kind of constricting
请注意  上流百货的顾客们
Attention, Upturn's shoppers
鞋店正在大促销
There's a sale in the shoe department
十楼
Tenth floor
快去
Come on
上流电梯公司
不会吧
No way
好多鞋啊
So many shoes
无意冒犯  珍珍
No offense, Pearly girl
我的脚可穿不来鞋
but my feet don't cotton much to shoes
俗话说得好
As the saying goes
大脚都有小鞋穿
there's a tiny shoe for every giant foot
能帮你穿吗
May I?
合脚就行
Well, if the shoe fits
你宰了我的细高跟
You slaughtered my stiletto
抱歉
Sorry
早提醒你了
I told you
等一下
Wait a minute
我认得你们两个
I know you two
你们就是刚刚那两个混混
You're those hooligans
通缉
狡诈鲸鱼来了
It's those wily whales
红色警报
Code red
上流小姐
Lady Upturn
抱歉
Sorry
我跟娜琳只是在玩
Narlene and I were just having some fun
玩
Fun?
购物可不是来玩的
Shopping is not supposed to be fun
幸好  我要禁止你们再来这里购物了
Fortunately for me, you'll never be shopping here again
可我有钻石不限量会员卡
But I had the diamond unlimited card
快  我们走
Come on, let's get
贵宾专用电梯
你们两位小姐不属于这里
You, young ladies, do not belong here
尤其是她
especially her
万一我朋友就是不肯
So what if my friend doesn't
学着城里人的样子做事呢
do things the way city people do?
起码她不会学你秀优越
At least she's not a stuck-up snob like you
并且
Besides
我们鲸鱼姐妹花一定要团结在一起
We cetacean sisters always stick together
钻石不限量卡
Diamond unlimited
接到了
I've got it
是我不好
My bad
蟹堡王把你当马使唤了
Looks like they worked you like a horse
对
Yeah
谢谢你陪我愉快出游  珍珍
Thanks for the whale's day out, Pearl
不过大城市实在太麻烦  不咋值
but the big city's more trouble than it's worth
以后你就来乡下玩吧
Next time, you're coming to the countryside
好  改天就去
Yeah, let's do that sometime
珍珍  你上流百货消费怎么这么多
Pearl, what's the deal with all these charges at Upturn's?
还等什么啊
Why wait?
马上就去乡下玩吧
Let's go to the countryside right now
再见了  老爸
Goodbye, Daddy
很快就回来
See you real soon
会特别特别快的
Sooner than you think
等等  等等
Wait, wait
你这是要去哪
Where do you think you're going?
不准走
You can't go away now
在吗
Hello?
有没有人
Anybody there?